

# Alberto Sanchez

GAME DEVELOPER in Barcelona, Spain

# CONTACT



(+34) 678 264 135



alberto93.dev@gmail.com



www.vosthek.com

# **SKILLS**

**Engines:** Unity, Unreal, Custom **Languages:** C/C++, C#, Python,

HLSL/GLSL, MaxScript

**Tools:** Visual\*, Git, SVN, 3DSMax, Maya, Adobe, RenderDoc, Nvidia

Nsight

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native
Catalan: Native
English: Advanced

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor in Computer Science**

Universitat Pompeu Fabra 2011-2016

# **Masters in Videogame Creation**

Universitat Pompeu Fabra 2017-2018

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Co-founder & Technical Director**

#### **Baby Robot Games**

[2019 - 2024]

- Co-founder of Baby Robot Games, videogame studio based in Spain, developed <u>Ereban: Shadow Legacy</u> in collaboration with <u>Raw Fury</u> publishing.
- Technical direction & management of the technical team. (Agile)
- Lead graphics programming (Shaders, Rendering pipeline)
- Lead, gameplay and tools programming.
- Performance & optimizations.

#### Software Engineer (Unity / C++)

Mobile Media Content

[2016 - 2019]

- Development of Unity3D AR/VR and desktop applications.
- Creation of a series of tooling pipelines for 3DSMax, Unity3D and AutoCAD.
- Research and development of computer graphics algorithms to automate and improve 3D virtual environments.

#### **Associate Professor**

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya

[2021 - Now]

• Tutor for undergraduate final degree videogame projects.

#### **Associate Professor**

Universitat La Salle

[2018 - 2021]

- Tools programming lecturer for Master's degree.
- Unity tools, 3DSMax & Custom Engine tools (C#, C++, Maxscript, Python).
- Definition of an asset integration pipeline using a custom engine.

#### **Software Engineer**

Avanade

[2015 - 2016]

- Dynamics AXS programmer at Avanade.
- Enterprise resource planning at greenfield project for Media Markt.

# **ABOUT ME**

Passionate about videogames since childhood, specially caught by the technology behind them.

I truly enjoy graphics and engine programming, where I always try to understand the low level first to better understand the high level.

I had the opportunity to co-found Baby Robot Games, where during five years I was in charge of the technical direction of the company, developing Ereban: Shadow Legacy.

I love to share knowledge of game development, making another of my passions to teach. I've given lectures at many different institutions, and I am a currently teaching at UOC University.

# **PROJECTS**

# **Ereban: Shadow Legacy**

Baby Robot Games (2019 - 2024)
Tags: C#, Unity, HDRP, HLSL, VFXGraph

Ereban: Shadow Legacy is a fast-paced stealth platformer game where you become Ayana, the last descendant of a forgotten race. Harness mystical shadow powers, high-tech gadgets and avoid or kill to uncover the truth about your past and the key to saving a dying, morally grey universe.

### <u> Atlas' Fate: Between Light & Darkness</u>

Baby Robot Games (2018)

Tags: C++, Directx, HLSL, Custom Engine

Atlas' Fate: Between Light & Darkness is a 3rd person stealth game where you take control of a stealth expert with the ability to merge with the shadows. This power allows him to move without being seen, move through walls, cushion falls or pass through obstacles.

# SIDE PROJECTS

## **Unknot Engine**

Self (2022)

Tags: Directx, C++, HLSL,

Custom engine developed from scratch, using DirectX. The aim of the engine is to create a basic engine template with its series of own tools to keep learning and improving the bases of graphics and engine programming.

#### **Assault Birds**

Self (2015)

Tags: Directx, C++, HLSL,

Videogame developed in C ++ from scratch using OpenGL. The aim of the project is to experiment with graphic programming, specially with shaders, creating reflections for water, shadows, water distortions and post-processing effects, among others.

## **COD-ModSource**

Self (2008)

Tags: C, QuakeScript

Series of Call of Duty 2 mods created in collaboration with the modder (Mitch Hubers). The mod reached top five popularity in the mod scene community.